DAVID COSTA

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER JAVA - MERN

david.costa.yafar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-costa-yafar/

(264) 15 464 7572

Portfolio: https://davidcosta92.github.io/porfolio-david-costa/ San Juan, Argentina



PROFILE

I have been working in health for 6 years, but now I am seeking new challenges in IT. I am currently completing a technical degree in software development, taking courses in specific technologies, and creating personal projects. I am a full-stack developer, but I would like to focus on backend development within a diverse and dynamic team. **I would love change the world through code!**

EDUCATION

Technician Degree in Web Development and Digital Applications - ISPC

2022 - 06/2024

Programming fundamentals, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), algorithms, Requirements analysis, UML design, SQL and NoSQL databases, Java, Python (Django/Flask), Android development with Java, Testing, Cybersecurity, Git, GitHub, Agile methodologies.

Backend JAVA SPRING SQL - Folcademy / San Juan Tec

12/2021 - 06/2023

Development of APIs with Java, Spring, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hibernate, Postman, Swagger, User management with Spring Security, JWT, Testing with Mockito Test containers, Spring email, Thymeleaf, Railway, and Bitbucket.

Full Stack React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB, SQL- Coderhouse

01/2022 - 06/2023

Node.js, Express, Mongo, Mongoose, sockets, Docker, Kubernetes, Artillery, unit and functional testing, Swagger, Firebase, REST API development and consumption, SQL language fundamentals, backups, functions, triggers, views, design, and normalization.

English level C2 Proficient EF SET Upper Intermediate

Other - Soft skills Analytical ability - Assertive communication - Effective negotiation - Teamwork - Problem-solving focus - Conflict resolution - Time management - Attention to detail

EXPERIENCE

Front end Developer React JS - Mecantronic

01/2023 - 04/2023

I worked on a project-based role to develop a landing page using React JS, as part of a real-world work experience proposal through Coderhouse. This was done as part of a team composed of UX/UI, SM, and PO, working remotely. My responsibilities included:

- Code the design in React JS, add functionalities, and test the final product. The main technologies used were React JS, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind, Swiper JS, Toastify, Email JS, Figma, Slack, Notion, Github, among others..
- We used the Scrum methodology to manage the project, with daily stand-ups for tracking and correcting deliverables, which allowed us to meet the client's deadlines and requirements satisfactorily.

Freelance experience - Portfolio Link [7]

Portfolio showcasing some of my latest projects where I performed tasks such as designing and diagramming database and project classes. Involved in design, development, documentation, deployment, and consumption of RESTful APIs. Utilized libraries such as Thymeleaf, Handlebars, Artillery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Materialize, Tailwind, Email Js, Mocha, etc.

Fullstack developer JAVA - React JS, API RESTFul Embarcadero

A system for managing boats, shifts, and rescue teams at each dam in the province, allowing for the maintenance of a record of boats that access, affected staff, and other vital data for statistics and analysis. The project is in the early stages of backend development, and then proceed to create the frontend for subsequent integration. In this stage, the survey, analysis, and design of the solution have already been carried out. Additionally, the first coding of the API has been initiated, using technologies such as:

Java, Spring, MySQL, Swagger, Spring Security, JWT, Mockito, Email Sender, etc.

Backend developer Python and Android JAVA, One Drop - Web y Mobile

Repository 7

05/2022 - 11/2023

Web development carried out in Angular - Django (Python) and mobile app in Android (Java), created to store and organize patient health records, and then accessed by a doctor. It was created in a scrum team, where I was responsible for leading the design and development of the backend, focusing on Java code and the design of MySQL and SQLite databases.

- We conducted daily stand-ups among the 8 team members, which facilitated excellent communication and rapid development.
- We achieved the objectives of each Sprint, overcoming technical difficulties, demonstrating great adaptability and resilience.

Backend developer JAVA - React Js, API RESTFul EduProject, JAM 2023

Repository 7

10/2023 - 12/2023

I worked on a web application for managing registrations, attendance, and academic users as part of the JAM 2023 event, aiming to create free software solutions for entrepreneurs. Based on a proposed problem, we analyzed potential solutions that led to the design and implementation of an MVP, using Java, Spring, MySQL, PostgreSQL, React JS, Swagger, Figma, Github, Notion, etc. My responsibilities included analyzing, designing, developing, and documenting the backend with Java - Spring and coding the frontend with React JS. The project was developed within a scrum team consisting of other developers, UX/UI designers, and POs, in an iterative and incremental process that met the objective of delivering an MVP to the client, exceeding expectations and allowing the business idea to be validated. We achieved a clear common objective, thanks to maintaining fluid and assertive communication among all team members.